<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-model href="http://docbook.org/xml/5.0/rng/docbook.rng" schematypens="http://relaxng.org/ns/structure/1.0"?>
<?xml-model href="http://docbook.org/xml/5.0/rng/docbook.rng" type="application/xml" schematypens="http://purl.oclc.org/dsdl/schematron"?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter [
<!ENTITY % ent SYSTEM "../conref.ent">
%ent;]
>
<chapter xmlns="http://docbook.org/ns/docbook" xmlns:xlink="http://www.w3.org/1999/xlink"
  version="5.0">
  <title>Titles</title>
  <para>Title styles differ depending on where they are used. To avoid typos, consider using
    entities, such as <code>&sa;</code>, for section names that are frequently used. To be
    consistent, leave out trailing colons within titles if they cannot be inserted
    systematically.</para>
  <section>
    <title>Book</title>
    <para>For a book, use a title that provides enough context. For example,
        <citetitle>&title-isg;</citetitle> clarifies that the style guide is about documentation
      rather than a programming language, and <emphasis>&ib;</emphasis> specifies that it is derived
      from &ib; rather than another entity.</para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <title>Chapter or section</title>
    <para>For a chapter or section, use a title that provides enough context without being
      redundant. In a chapter titled <citetitle>Lists</citetitle>, for example, use section titles
        <citetitle>Ordered</citetitle> and <citetitle>Unordered</citetitle> rather than
        <citetitle>Ordered list</citetitle> and <citetitle>Unordered list</citetitle>.</para>
  </section>
  <section>
    <title>Procedure</title>
    <para>For a procedure, use a title that starts with a <link
        xlink:href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gerund">gerund</link> (also known as a verb with an
        <literal>-ing</literal> ending), such as <literal>Writing</literal> in the example that
      follows. Doing so keeps the procedure name short, and distinguishes the name of a procedure
      from its steps that start with action verbs.</para>
    <procedure>
      <title>Writing a procedure</title>
      <para>If there are any prerequisites, list them here or provide a link to additional
        information.</para>
      <step>
        <para>Create a new file (<literal>File</literal> → <literal>New...</literal>).</para>
      </step>
      <step>
        <para>Write an action verb at the start of each instruction.</para>
        <para>For a list of action words, see <link
            xlink:href="http://teaching.uncc.edu/learning-resources/articles-books/best-practice/goals-objectives/writing-objectives"
            >Bloom's taxonomy</link>.</para>
      </step>
      <step>
        <para>Name the file similar to that of the procedure.</para>
        <para>For example, this procedure's file name could be
            <filename>writing-a-procedure.xml</filename>.</para>
      </step>
      <step>
        <para>Separate any additional information from the main instruction.</para>
        <para>For example, previous steps and this one each contain an additional sentence that is
          not on the same line as the instruction.</para>
      </step>
    </procedure>
  </section>
</chapter>
